In this lesson, we're going to learn how to organize our TypeScript code using modules and
namespaces.
We're going to focus mainly on modules and using the keywords import and export because
that's how modern TypeScript applications are structured.
A good code organization is just as important as good typing.
As our application is growing, putting everything in one file is going to quickly become
unmanageable because, of course, it's going to be hard to read, hard to maintain.
We're going to have many name code illusions and it's going to be pretty much difficult to
use.
So we're going to need a way to split our code into logical, reasonable paces.
So in TypeScript, our module is simply a file that uses the import or export keywords.
So basically one file equals one module.
And each module is going to have its own scope which helps prevent naming conflicts.
So let's start by exporting something for a file.
So I'm going to remove what we have here.
Let's create a function here, export, function, and it's going to take two parameters,
a and b, we've seen this before, multiple times the course, a and b, and it's just going
to return number.
And let's just give the implementation of return a plus b.
Now when you hover over this, notice now we get a message because it's saying that we
can't use our modifier on this varo value to calculations without using this option.
So what this means is we need to learn to find it as a type rather than just a straightforward
function.
This is a change in the more recent version of TypeScript to do export type function.
Let's now define another function, perhaps, a sports function called its subtract in two
numbers, number a and b, and it's also going to return a number, and we're going to return
a minus b.
Now this export keyword makes our functions available to other files.
So let's now import these functions into another file, so I'm just going to create another
file here, let's call it hello to rubbish names, but let's just stick with it.
Now to import, let's make sure I see the file as opposed to import, now we define, we'll
bring in the functions, so it has to add and subtract.
This is coming from our hello dot ts file, this is coming from the same folder and then
let us tell it to 30 cents, hello here, add and subtract, now we can do console log called
these functions, add and supply the two parameters, five and three, then console log, subtract.
Let's just do the same, five and three, and this is going to allow us to reuse our code
to find in this module anywhere else we want without copying it, a module could also have
a default export, I'm just going to come to our hello again, and let's just create a default
export, by doing export the default function, let's have a function called log, let's
just pass a message of string, it's not going to return anything, so void, just do console
log message for a very simple function here, now this is a default, by what we do, we come
to our hello to here, is rather than pushing a brackets, what we do instead is we just, just
put the word the function we need, which is log, that's the defaults function, so no bracket
here, now we could just do whatever we want and just do log, hello, as well as example,
but sometimes you may find also that there might be some clashing of names when we have
a whole load of different files, so you can actually create an alias, what we do is we
use the word as, so log as, make us say logger, for example, you may also find occasionally
that you get some con naming conflicts, if you have a lot of modules, perhaps there's
another function called ads, and you're having the multiple imports, so how do you get
around that, so you can then alias it by using the as, and so as, let's say ads numbers, now
we just change it to add numbers, like it's got here, add numbers, oops, that's my
totally sense, isn't really working very well today, so they're going forward when you
start to have a bigger project, but you're not going to call your file hello, and that's
very kind of silly, you're going to give it a much better name, just to sort of throw
a project, but what I suggest you do is you create yourself a sort of structure, and first
of all, I would create a folder called source, and inside your source, what maybe wants
to create a folder for the modules, so let's call it modules, you're going to put all
your TS files inside that modules folder, and you might then have another folder for doing
utilities, so it creates another folder, and call it utils, for example, and so my source
folder, I'm going to create another folder called utils for anything else, this is going
to keep your code together as well as being easy to find.